childcare.co.uk 2018-10-05

# Privacy and Cookies Policy - Childcare.co.uk

Effective Date: 24/05/2018

## 1. Who are we?

1.1 We are International New Media Limited trading as Childcare.co.uk. For privacy queries, you can contact us at dataprotection@childcare.co.uk. Other contact details are on our website. 

## 2. What’s the point of this policy?

2.1 It tells you what to expect when we collect your personal information. Please only use our service if you are completely happy with this policy. 

2.2 Generally, the policy covers only information provided to us. If you give personal information to other people, such as payment providers or other websites to which we link, such as online training courses, insurance services and discount schemes, please check their privacy policies. 

## 3. Might the policy change?

3.1 Yes. We will post any new version on our website (please check whenever you visit the site) and also notify you by email, SMS, in-app message or otherwise. We will assume you agree to the new version of the policy if you use our site or app after its effective date. 

## 4. What do we collect? 

4.1 Information which you upload to our service or otherwise give us such as your name, postcode, contact details, date of birth as well as any personal information which you include in (a) documents which you upload to our service or (b) your public activities on our service, e.g. reviews.

4.2 Automated information such as the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your device to the internet, connection information such as browser type and version, information about your device including device-type and device identifier, operating system and platform, mobile network data, a unique reference number linked to the data you enter on our system, login details, the site from which you arrived at our service, details of your activity with date / time stamps including pages you visited and your searches / transactions. 

4.3 If you log in via Facebook: Information provided by Facebook including your name, email address, date of birth and general location.

## 5. What’s our reason / legal basis for collecting the information?

5.1 Because it’s necessary to provide you with our services under our contract with you. We may use it for other purposes (such as email marketing) if you consent. In the case of other data such as automated information collected when you browse our site, we use this to manage and improve our service (including security and fraud prevention) in accordance with our “legitimate interests”.

## 6. What about cookies?

6.1 We and/or third parties use cookies and other tracking technologies on our website. A cookie is an identifier (a small file of letters and numbers) that is sent to your computer. Our website’s functionality will be limited if you configure your browser to reject cookies. 

6.2 Cookies are widely used to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the website owner or others. Session cookies are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser only until your browser is closed. They allow websites to link your actions during a browser session. Persistent cookies stay in the cookie file of your browser for longer (how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie). For further information on cookies, including how to use your browser to block them and how to delete cookies already stored on your device, visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

6.3 The following kinds of cookies may be used on this website:

a) Session cookies: These are essential for our service and enable us to keep track of your movement from page to page and store your selections so you do not get asked repeatedly for the same information. They allow you to proceed through many pages of the site quickly and easily without having to authenticate or reprocess each new area you visit. For example, a session cookie remembers your shopping cart selection so you will have the items you selected when you are ready to check out. 

b) Mobile app session IDs: Similarly, these are used to authenticate you while you are using our mobile app. 

c) Facebook cookies: Facebook places third party persistent cookies (up to a year) to authenticate you if you log in via Facebook. Click [here](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) for more information. If you register or log into our service via Facebook, you will be automatically logged into our service as long as you remain logged in to Facebook. If you specifically log out of our service, we place a persistent cookie to prevent the automatic login happening on future visits.

d) Referral cookies: Persistent cookies (up to 30 days) are placed to track referrals from websites affiliated with us so we can pay affiliates and assess the effectiveness of the affiliate links. 

e) Google cookies: Persistent cookies (up to four years we believe) are set in connection with the following Google services on our site and these cookies may involve certain information (such as your IP address and web address of the page you’re visiting) being sent to Google:

i) Google Analytics (“GA”): We use cookies to recognise and count the number of website visitors as well as providing other information about the visit such as duration, route through the website and what sites the visitor came from. This information helps us to improve the way our website works, for example by making sure users find what they need easily. You can specifically opt out of GA [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). See below for other opt out routes.

ii) GA Advertising Features: We may use the following GA Advertising Features: Remarketing with GA / Google Display Network Impression Reporting / GA Demographics and Interest Reporting / Integrated services that require GA to collect data via advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers. These features involve GA collecting data via Google or other advertising cookies including for display of ads which may be of interest based on your visits to this and other sites. You can specifically opt out of GA [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). You can opt of GA Advertising Features at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices). See below for other opt out routes. 

iii) Google advertising cookies (AdSense, Doubleclick): Google uses cookies in connection with Google advertising on our website to serve ads to you based on your visits to this and other websites, to avoid showing you repeat ads and for various other purposes. You can opt out at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices). See below for other opt out routes

More information and opt out: Click [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=uk) for Google’s privacy policy and [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/types?hl=en-GB&gl=uk) for more information about the kinds of cookies placed by Google. Click [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) for information about how Google uses data from its partners’ sites or apps as well as different ways to opt out of Google cookies. 

f) Gosquared cookies: Cookies are used on our site to enable Gosquared analytics services. See [here](https://www.gosquared.com/legal/privacy/statement/) for more details including opt out information.

g) Social media cookies: We may use various social media sharing and other features including: [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) and [Twitter](https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies). These features may involve the relevant companies using cookies or linking your visit with cookies previously placed by them on your computer in order for them to collect information relating to your visit to our website or your interaction with their services or otherwise. Click the links shown above for further information including how to opt out where this is possible. 

h) Cookie-warning cookie: This cookie takes note of whether you are happy to accept cookies on this website based on your response to the message which appeared when you first visited the website. This persistent cookie will remember your preference for up to 90 days. 

## 7. What do we do with personal information? 

7.1 Provide our service, e.g. send service messages, provide local search results, process payments, fulfil orders. 

7.2 Send you marketing messages, if you have given permission. You can withdraw permission at any time as explained on our service or by emailing us at the above email address. 

7.3 Use it to recognise you when you visit or return to our service to track anonymised traffic and usage patterns, prevent or detect fraud or abuses and help us improve our service. 

## 8. How long do we keep it? 

8.1 We will generally keep your information for up to six years after your account is closed - for tax reasons and/or to help deal with any disputes. That timeframe may vary if we are legally required to keep information for a particular period. We will keep your information which we use for marketing until you tell us to stop sending you marketing messages. 

## 9. To whom do we send or make available your personal information? 

9.1 To other people who supply us with a service, e.g. e-commerce platform providers, website hosts, content delivery networks and businesses which help us send communications, gather feedback or monitor our website. 

9.2 To the relevant insurance provider, if you opt in to the insurance scheme offered on our service. This information will include your name, contact details, childminder status and employer reference number, if applicable.

9.3 To other users of our service, if you enter personal information into a public profile or otherwise include it in a review or other public action on our service. Or if you give other users access to your documents which include personal information (e.g. regulatory certifications or criminal record checks). You can control your privacy settings at [www.childcare.co.uk/myprivacy](https://www.childcare.co.uk/myprivacy). Your profile and reviews will be automatically removed from our site if you close your account.

9.4 To the police or other relevant authorities or to complainants, if we think the personal information breaches our terms and conditions, or it is necessary to protect us or others, or that a criminal offence may have been committed, or where required by law or where requested by the police or other appropriate authorities.

9.5 To potential buyers so far as reasonably necessary, in the case of an actual or proposed (including negotiations for a) sale or merger or business combination involving all or the relevant part of our business.

## 10. What happens to your payment details?

10.1 These go direct to our payment partners. We do not receive such information except as stated above. To ensure your details are not being used without consent, our payment partners may send your personal information to relevant third parties including credit reference and fraud prevention agencies, who may keep a record of that information.

## 11. Do we send your information outside the European Union?

11.1 Your personal information which we collect is stored within the EU and is not transferred to any third countries except for the following.

11.2 Your personal information may be transferred to the US by the following companies certified under the [EU-US Privacy Shield Framework](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en), which provides certain safeguards for your personal information: Google (analytics and “Crashlytics”), Mixpanel (analytics), Mailchimp (email delivery), Postmark (Wildbit LLC – email delivery), Paypal (payment), Recurly (payment), Rollbar (error reporting), Slack (online tools).

## 12. What rights do you have? 

12.1 If the legal requirements are met: To ask us for access to your personal information, to rectify it if there are mistakes, to delete or restrict or object to its use in certain circumstances or to “data portability”. 

12.2 If you have a complaint about how we are dealing with your personal information, please contact us via the email address above. If you are not happy with our response or think we are not handling your personal information in accordance with the law, you can complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).

12.3 For more information about your rights, visit the ICO’s website: [www.ico.org.uk](https://www.ico.org.uk/).

**Version: 2.0 Revision C0AD12E**
